## Melissa M. Patterson

melizzap.github.io melissa.patterson.va@gmail.com 757.846.7853 Chicago, IL

## **Summary**

After I finished my undergraduate degree, I commissioned as an officer in the Air Force and spent 4 years traveling the world as a laser physicist. While I enjoyed the work I did there, I found the military lifestyle to be quite difficult and dangerous. So in early 2014 I decided to switch gears and enter the world of software development. It has been an amazing ride. I love that I learn something new almost every day, whether it be an approach to problem, a technology, or a development process. I like to spend my free time picking apart websites that display data in interest ways or building small programs that make my life a little easier. I spend most of my time doing front end development in JavaScript, though, I often try work across multiple teams at a company. In my most recent role at NextTier Education, I worked primarily with TypeScript and Angular2. Ideally, I'd love to work on a medium to large sized software team practicing agile or scrum style development.

<u>Languages</u>

**Frameworks** 

JavaScript, Python, Ruby, HTML, CSS

Angular2, React, Django, Rails, AngularJS

**Experience** 

NextTier Education Chicago, IL

Web Developer Mar 2017 - Oct 2017

- Worked on a component based web application software using TypeScript/JavaScript Angular2
- Led a team of developers on projects starting with rough requirements all the way through to complete features

The Onion Chicago, IL
Web Developer Dec 2015 - Mar 2017

- Built and maintained features for all Onion Inc. properties: The Onion, Clickhole, the Avclub, and OnionStudios
- Started learning series that focused on new technologies and building fun side projects for the Onion, including an Onion headline slackbot, Onionbot
- Built client-facing features, such as the continuous article reading lists on Clickhole and The Avclub and a reusable timeline retrospective template, http://www.theonion.com/interactive/biden

OpinionlabChicago, IL

Rails/JavaScript Engineer

Apr 2014 - Dec 2015

- Developed a web application using Ruby on Rails, Angular, and Elasticsearch
- Part of a 5 person self-driven team practicing agile/scrum development
- Maintained and upgraded legacy comment card system built in XSL by implementing ES6\

## Air Force Research Lab

Fort Sam-Houston, TX

Lead Laser Evaluation Physicist

Nov 2010 - Nov 2014

- Led a laser evaluation team of 7 with annual budget of \$1.5M, managed laser safety for 33 programs, 200+ personnel and a \$50M facility
- Developed and tested ESRI based software for military-wide implementation, replacing antiquated software and increasing footprint accuracy by 26%
- Published 30 technical reviews and two studies for external customers

**Education** 

University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA
Bachelors - Physics May 2010